What's going on everyone? I'm James with the School of Hard Knocks. I'm here with
Josh and today we're linking up with a really good friend of mine, Jacob Hopkins.
Jacob, at 19 years old, went from being a college dropout, took more
than $10,000 in debt, and now making over $250,000 a year in sales.
So today, here at Jacob's place, I'm going to talk to
him, get some tips from him about sales in today's world.
What's going on, big man?
What up, James?
How you doing, bro?
What up, Josh?
How you doing, man?
Who are we here with right here?
Right here?
Yeah.
This is Quinn Fulmer. I do all
the YouTube side of stuff at acquisition.com.
Alex and Layla.
So you've been in content. You've seen a lot of creators grow. What would
be your best piece of advice to a content creator starting out in 2022?
I'd say short form is the way to get people into the door, but to the
same extent, don't sell out and just try to be a bunch of different other people.
Everyone's got their own unique way of doing things.
Stay true to yourself because it's a long game.
You can get followers doing all this short stuff and trying to build an audience really
fast, but if you do that and you build it on a foundation that's not you,
it's just not going to work.
It's just not going to work.
It's just not going to go anywhere.
Except that it's going to be three, five
years, 10 year game, and then you're good.
How did you guys meet?
He was editing the video and then I
think we just started DMing back and forth.
Two days ago or was it last night?
You're just like, hey, let's meet up.
Let's film some videos. Let's do it.
And so I was kind of giving a brief little introduction
to you before we came in here and started the video,
but give a little rundown to everyone about yourself, kind of how
you got to where you are today and started crushing the sales game.
So I started out in high school.
I was always super business minded,
always looking for the next hustle.
I never really wanted to go to college.
I just didn't feel like it aligned with.
Having the freedom that I wanted because I knew I never wanted
to just live like a normal life or like an average life.
As I was going through that, I started multiple businesses.
I started a car detailing business.
I started, you know, a drop shipping business.
I did real estate.
So I was just trying to
figure out what I should do next.
What's going to make the money?
And I had a little bit of success
with a couple of the companies, but nothing major.
I made a couple grand.
It was cool.
It was fun.
And then really figuring out which school,
which college I was supposed to go to.
I picked Pepperdine.
It was the only school that didn't open.
It ended up, you know, kind of giving me this.
This opportunity to be able to get
into sales and kind of start that career.
It's been about two years since
then and haven't looked back since.
I love that, man.
And the main reason we're here today is we want to get your five best sales tips and
lessons that you've learned since you've been in sales for someone who's just now starting out in sales.
Let's do it.
You guys want to go chop it on the balcony?
Let's check out the view.
Let's do it.
What would be your best five tips to
someone who's just now starting out in sales?
Number one would definitely be volume negates luck.
The way I got my foot in the
door was, you know, I had Alex Hermosi.
He owns a company called.
And I was losing so much money with my company.
I was doing real estate and I
was losing three, four grand a month.
And he said, hey, man, the reason you're losing
so much money is because you suck at sales.
He said, if everyone's making 100 calls, make 200.
Long story short, I hopped in and I made 200,
300, 400 dials a day when everyone else was making 100.
Within two, three weeks, I was doing just as good
as everyone else because I just was putting up more numbers.
Sales is a really high performance job.
It's really, you know, you got
to be on it all the time.
How do you maintain a high performance?
It sounds kind of like cheesy, but just
make sure you're taking care of your health.
You're getting sleep.
You're doing the things that you need to do.
And I think the biggest thing
that causes stress for me is inaction.
So if I'm not hitting the phones, if I'm not doing
what I know I need to do, then I get stressed out.
I don't focus in on the result.
I focus in on the action.
And if you look at it like that, you just focus in on what
you're doing day to day and then have the action kind of just happen.
How about number two?
So number two is listen more, talk less.
So I feel like a lot of people get
into sales and they feel like it's a talking job.
Of course, you have to be articulate.
You have to know what you're going to say.
But people think, you know, in my experience that
they're not really listening to what the person is saying.
They're just trying to wait their turn to talk.
And so really with that, just being able to practice active listening, really understanding what
people's needs are, what they want, why they're actually doing the things or buying the product.
You build so much trust and rapport with that person.
And then you can close the sale.
When I pitch, it's less than a minute.
Say, hey, here's the three things
based on what you told me.
Customize a little bit.
Short and sweet.
Keep my powder dry.
But I was able to listen and ask him.
Such good questions that before I even
pitched, they knew they wanted to buy.
If you could go back in time and have a conversation with
your younger self, what's the best piece of advice you'd give yourself?
I think people just need to bet on themselves.
Like if I were to tell my younger
self, it's like just continue to bet on yourself.
Look at things through a long time horizon.
When I first started entrepreneurship, I tried
to become a millionaire in 90 days.
You can get very, very lucky.
But if you want a safe bet
on becoming a millionaire, think in 10 years.
Think what skill sets do I need to acquire
to be able to do what I need to do?
What is your dream business?
Do you need to be able to sell for it?
Go learn sales.
Stack.
If you're a millionaire, go learn sales.
Go learn sales.
Then start buying the next skill sets.
What I wanted to do did not
align with my 10-year journey, my 10-year path.
So that brings us into number three.
So number three would be challenge people.
In sales, people try to relationship sell.
They try to be that person's friend.
And in sales, I'm not your friend.
But at the same time, I
care about you enough to challenge you.
A lot of people just try to be super, super
agreeable and super, yeah, yeah, yeah, we can do that.
We can do that.
Not challenging their beliefs on how they
should do something by asking the right questions.
So if you're able to
get the frame of the conversation,
where you're the understanding expert,
and then you're in a
place where you can challenge them.
I mean, think, your parents challenge you
all the time because they care about you.
You can't just, you know, be buddy-buddy with someone
and expect them to buy a high-ticket product.
And could you give me an example
of like how you would challenge someone
if you're on like a sales call?
You know, in my market, we help gym owners grow.
There's a lot of limiting beliefs in that.
And they say, hey, you know,
the way I'm going to grow
is I'm just going to be doing word of mouth.
And like the easiest way to challenge that is
you said you want to double your gym
membership in the next, you know, two years.
Do you think you're going to gain 300 members?
By word of mouth in the next two years?
Or do you think there's a better way?
You're challenging them on that rather than just saying,
oh, yeah, yeah, that's great.
You should do that.
So for new people that are getting the sale,
something that may intimidate them is
the fact that it's primarily commission only.
How did you get over that initially?
There's nothing guaranteed.
People have this unrealistic expectation that
they're going to go to college.
They're going to get a job
and they just get a guaranteed salary.
If you don't do a good
job, you're going to get fired.
Would you rather be put on a salary?
Or would you rather go
out and based on your performance,
you get paid based on that.
And it's not for everyone.
But it's the closest thing to owning a business.
And if you want to be an
entrepreneur, you want to be a business owner,
you can go in and learn how
to manage your time, manage your schedule,
be your own boss.
And then you actually get paid
for how much work you do.
All right.
And what about number four?
Ask for money, right?
I mean, I feel like
too many people get into sales
and they don't relentlessly ask for the order.
So once you're in the position where
don't pitch until you know you can close.
Once you pitch and you know
you can close, actually ask for it.
I've had people tell me no
five, ten times in a row,
but I continue to solve the problem and ask again.
How?
High percentage of salespeople don't even ask
for the order and ask for the deal.
How important has networking been to
your career so far in sales?
I mean, I think networking is very important
and it depends what type of sales, right?
So the way my sales process works is,
you know, I have clients that see an ad,
they click on the ad and
they jump on a call with me.
So they jump into the program.
But then I continue to follow up
with the clients that are in the program
and ask them if they know
anyone else, if they have any referrals.
And over the last week, I've closed just
two deals from being able to do that.
It is important.
You want to make sure you kind of,
nurture the relationship in the right way.
When people are first getting started in sales,
they're probably stressed out because
they're probably not that good yet.
How did you get over that initial stress?
Stress is a normal feeling.
Like first you got to register.
It's like you're going to feel
stressed even when you're doing good
because you're always worried about what's next.
So like humans just experience stress.
So if you can just understand
that's a feeling and it doesn't matter,
that's like step one.
Step two, if you're feeling stressed, just do more things.
Like just put in more work, watch more game tape,
listen to more sales calls,
really just do whatever you can
to be able to take action.
Because the more action you're
taking, the less bored you are.
And the more bored you
are, the more stressed I get.
What would your fifth tip be
to someone who's getting into sales?
Closers ask hard questions.
Too many people are scared, you
know, to ask those hard questions.
How much money is in your bank account?
What happens if you don't fix this problem?
What does your life look like in
five years if you don't solve this?
What does it look like if it
does happen the way you want it to?
You have to be able to ask these hard questions,
the things that you need to know
to put the prospect in the best position.
I can't sign someone up into our program
if they don't have enough money to be successful.
But the only reason I can know that is because,
hey, I'm going to ask that hard question.
I'm going to really figure out.
And it's awkward at first, right?
It's hard.
But once you, you know, get used to it,
then you can ask hard questions.
You can have hard conversations.
And there's this saying in life,
it's like the more hard conversations you have,
the more successful you are.
So if you can build that skill set
of being able to ask those hard questions,
then you can just get so much further.
So that wraps up today's video with Jacob Hopkins
and his five best tips to younger
people who are starting out in sales today.
Jacob, we learned a lot today.
Thank you for joining us.
School of Hard Knocks.
I appreciate you.
Where can everyone find you?
Instagram, Jacob Hopkins.
Make sure you like, leave us a
subscribe at the School of Hard Knocks.
A lot of amazing content on the way.
Let's go.